University Senate; Records ua200
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Subject Files, 1965-1999; 13; 1.67 cubic ft.
  - University operations Committee - Publication "Trends in Instruction - Class Sizes, Course Offerings, Methods of Instruction: An Analysis of CASA Data", 1996 April (Box 3 (13-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Distance Learning Committee of the University Faculty Senate Interim Report, 1995 January (Box 3 (13-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Faculty Senate Bulletin, 1995-1997 (Box 3 (13-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Faculty Senate Bulletin, 1997-1998 (Box 3 (13-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Conference on Instructional Technologies (CIT) - Seventh Annual, 1998 (Box 3 (13-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Faculty Senate Bulletin, 1998-1999 (Box 3 (13-Subject Files), Folder 18)
- Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies, 1962-1999; 14; 1.17 cubic ft.
  Records of Senate Committiees and Task Forces without permanent, standing status.
  - Collections Committee, 1962-1963 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 1)
  - University Bookstore Advisory Board, 1966 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 2)
  - Faculty Affairs Council, 1966-1969 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 3)
  - Grievance and Complaint Committee, 1967-1972 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 4)
  - Senate Colloquium for NYEA or UUP, 1967-1972; 1978 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 5)
  - Personnel Policies Council Agendas and Minutes, 1968 January-1969 October (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 6)
  - Personnel Policies Council Faculty Handbook Committee, 1968 October- 1969 May (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 7)
  - Personnel Policies Council Reports to Senate, 1968 September-1969 December (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 8)
  - Personnel Policies Council Social and Charitable Activities Committee, 1968 December-1969 May (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 9)
  - Personnel Policies Council Treasurer's Reports, 1968 January-1969 May (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 10)
  - Personnel Policies Council Reports, 1968-1970 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 11)
  - Personnel Policies Council Annual Reports, 1968-1969; 1971-1972 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 12)
  - Personnel Policies Council Correspondence, 1968 June-1971 May (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 13)
  - Personnel policies council Committee on Academic Freedom and Professional Ethics and Grievance Procedures, 1968 October-1969 October; Undated (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 14)
  - Personnel Policies Council Parking Committee, 1969 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 15)
  - Personnel Policies Council Faculty Economic and Professional Welfare Committee, 1969 October-1970 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 16)
  - Faculty-Student Consultation Guidelines Ad Hoc Committee, 1969 May-1971 May (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 17)
  - Awards and opportunities for Advanced Study Committee, 1969-1973 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 18)
  - Search Committee for President, 1969-1978 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 19)
  - Environmental Decisions Commission, 1969-1979 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 20)
  - Academic Regulations, Task Force on, 1970 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 21)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Senatorial Authority, 1970 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 22)
  - Faculty Evaluation and Term Renewal, Tenure and Promotion Criteria Ad Hoc Committee, 1970 December-1971 April (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 23)
  - Graduate Teaching Assistants, Report of the Committee on the Training of, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 24)
  - Personnel Policies Council Parking Committee, 1970 March-1971 December (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 25)
  - Personnel Policies Council Treasurer's Reports, 1970 November-1971 May (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 26)
  - Personnel Policies Council Bills and Resolutions, 1970-1972 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 27)
  - Personnel Policies Council Reports to Senate, 1970 May; 1972 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 28)
  - University Evaluation and Improvement Council, 1970 November-1972 May (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 29)
  - Outstanding Teaching Awards Committee, 1970-1975 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 30)
  - Instruction, Task Force on, 1970; 1978 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 31)
  - Judicial Workshop Steering Committee, 1971 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 32)
  - Senate Professional Association (SPA), 1971 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 33)
  - Personnel Policies Council Agendas and Minutes, 1971-1972 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 34)
  - Personnel Policies Council Correspondence, 1971 September-1972 July (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 35)
  - Personnel Policies Council Grievance Committee, 1971 October-1972 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 36)
  - Personnel Policies Council Faculty Handbook Committee, 1971 October-1972 January (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 37)
  - Personnel Policies Council SPA/PPC Joint Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 38)
  - Council on University Evaluation and Improvement, 1972 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 39)
  - Grants for the Improvement of Undergraduate Instruction, Campus Committee for, 1972 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 40)
  - Personnel Policies Council Group Insurance, 1972 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 41)
  - University Scholars Ad Hoc Committee, 1972 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 42)
  - Personnel Policies Council Parking Committee, 1972 January -1973 April (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 43)
  - Committee on Discretionary Salary Increases, 1972-1974 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 44)
  - Committee on Student Evaluation of Teachers, 1972-1974 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 45)
  - Academic Services Council, 1972 January-1976 May (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 46)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on By-Laws, 1973-1974 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 47)
  - Academic Program Priorities, Select Committee on, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 48)
  - Academic Program Priorities, Report of Select Committee on, 1975 May 15 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 49)
  - Ad-Hoc Committee of Cognate Disciplines on Promotion and Continuing Appointment, 1975 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 50)
  - Concerned Faculty, the Committee of, 1976-1977 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 51)
  - Search Committee for Vice President, 1976-1979 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 52)
  - Search Committee for Assistant Vice President for Academic Affairs, 1977-1978; Undated (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 53)
  - Undergraduate Education, Special Committee on, 1979 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 54)
  - Regulations of the Commissioner of Education, Ad Hoc Committee on the, 1979-1980 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 55)
  - University Senate Study Committee, 1980 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 56)
  - Distribution Requirements, Report of the Special Committee on, 1981 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 57)
  - Archives of Public Affairs and Policy Ad-Hoc Faculty Advisory Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 58)
  - Student Ethics and Cheating, Task Force on, 1982-1983 (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 59)
  - Task Force on Library Construction, 1985; 1987-1990; Undated (Box 1 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 60)
  - Steering Committee for Planning For Review of Undergraduate Education, 1976; 1977; Undated (Box 2 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 1)
  - Committee on Faculty Names, 1987-1988 (Box 2 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 2)
  - Facilities Names, Committee on, 1987-1988 (Box 2 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 3)
  - Sexuality Week, Ad Hoc Committee to Review, 1989 (Box 2 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 4)
  - Sexuality Week, Ad Hoc Committee to Review; Review Materials-Pamphlets, 1989 (Box 2 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 5)
  - Committee on Academic Dishonesty, 1989-1990 (Box 2 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 6)
  - University Mission Task Force, 1991-1999 (Box 2 (14-Temporary and Ad Hoc Bodies), Folder 7)
- Councils and Committees, 1950-2011; 15; 16.69 cubic ft.
  - Executive Committee, 1966-1999; 15.1; 3.17 cubic ft.
    This series includes agendas and minutes of the Executive Committee of the Faculty and University Senate, Executive Committee Reports, and general correspondence relating to its responsibility for the general operations of the senate. The Executive Committee is responsible for preparing the agendas for the senate meetings. It also has "urgency powers" to act for the University Senate whenever it is impractical to convene the Senate to make a decision. However, any actions taken under this provision must be approved retroactively by the Senate. The Executive Committee also may serve in an advisory capacity to the President of the University ( Faculty Handbook, 1984, p. 12). Also included in this series are audio cassettes of Executive Committee Meetings (1987-88,90)
  - Governance Council, 1967-1994; 15.2; 0.67 cubic ft.
    This series contains memoranda, correspondence, proposals and reports. The Governance Commission was responsible for developing and revising the by-laws of the University Senate as well as dealing with other matters concerning the governance of the University Senate as a whole. The Governance Commission has been variously called the Special Committee to Review Faculty By-Laws, the Ad Hoc Committee on Faculty-Student Governance, the Committee on University Governance, the Governance Committee, the University Governance Commission, and the University Commission on Governance. The Ad Hoc Committee on Faculty-Student Governance was formed in 1969 to review Faculty by-laws and recommend revision, and to fashion ways of involving students more in the development of University Policy, "perhaps through the formation of a University-wide Senate" (Governance Commission, Records, 200/20/01). The records in this series from 1967 and 1968 consist of reports by the Faculty Governance Sub-Committee of the state-wide University Faculty Senate. These reports appear to have been the catalyst that led to the formation of the Governance Commission which is responsible for the relationship between the Senate and the councils, schools, and colleges. The SUNYA Governance Commission records reflect the working out of these questions as well as the admission of administrative personnel and students to the University Senate. This series also contains the records of the Committee on Faculty By-Laws (1962-84, 1988-90). This committee continues to review and revise the University faculty by-laws. Also included are University Faculty Senate by-laws and manuals, meeting reports, general SUNY-wide correspondence, ad-hoc SUNY center committees, and policies of the Board of Trustees.
  - Graduate Academic Council (GAC), 1961-1997; 15.3; 1.67 cubic ft.
    This series includes agendas and minutes, annual reports, bills and resolutions, and correspondence of the Graduate Academic Council, created in 1961 as the Graduate Council. The Council has responsibility for implementing graduate academic planning as established by the Council on Educational Policy ( Faculty Handbook, 1984, pp. 21-22). The Graduate Academic Council has been concerned with residence requirements (1971), credit transfer policy, guidelines for independent study and research investigations, the conferral of degrees, and the evaluation, revision, and adoption of academic programs. The Graduate Academic Council predates the formation of the Faculty Senate, having functioned as a general council of the College independent of the Faculty Council ( Faculty Handbook, 1962, p. 20). The Graduate Council was created on May 26, 1961, by the Graduate Faculty and replaced the Committee on Doctoral Studies (established in 1960) and the Committee on Graduate Studies (a subcommittee of the Academic Council); the Council also assumed the responsibilities for graduate study that had been the province of the Academic Council (Report of the Graduate Council, May 7, 1962).
  - Undergraduate Academic Council (UAC), 1950-1999; 15.4; 4 cubic ft.
    Arranged alphabetically and chronologically thereafter. T
  - Council on Research (COR), 1966-1998; 15.5; 0.5 cubic ft.
    Includes agendas, minutes, annual reports, reports to the Senate, and correspondence. The Research Council is empowered to review research activities, to consider ways in which the University can increase the effectiveness of its research activities, to review procedures of research conducted on campus when human subjects are involved, to set safety standards, and to allocate research funds within the university.
    Also includes the records of committees and policies of the Research Council. The Research Council has drafted the SUNYA Research Policy (1970), the Human Subjects Policy (1977), formed the Biohazards Committee (1977), established funding for research, and instituted the Writing Center (1978). Included in the series are the records of the Recombinant DNA Research Committee.
  - Council on Promotions & Continuing Appointments (CPCA), 1967-1993; 15.6; 0.5 cubic ft.
    This series includes minutes, annual reports, bills and resolutions, and correspondence. The council recommends individuals for promotions in rank and for continuing appointment ( Faculty Handbook, 1984, p.26).
    Also includes the records of CPCA committees. These include the Faculty Evaluation & Personnel Action Committee (1970), the Faculty-Student Committee on Tenure (1968-69), and the Subcommittee on Promotions and Continuing Appointments (1972-74).
  - Committee on Academic Freedom, Freedom of Expression, & Community Responsibility (CAFFECoR), 1972-1998; 15.7; 0.5 cubic ft.
    This series contains agendas and minutes (1972-98) and reports to the Senate (1972-82). The Council considers problems and recommends policies concerning matters of academic freedom and standards of professional ethics both inside and outside the university community (Faculty Handbook, 1984, p 25.) The Council on Academic Freedom and Ethics deals with matters concerning student grievances and professional codes of ethics. The predecessor of the Council on Academic Freedom and Ethics was the Committee on Academic Freedom of the Faculty Council (Faculty Handbook, 1962, p. 16).
  - Council on Libraries, Information Systems, & Computing (LISC), 1966-1996; 15.8; 0.5 cubic ft.
    This series includes agendas and minutes, annual reports, bills and resolutions, correspondence, and reports to the Senate. The responsibilities of the Library Council include establishing policies for the library and guidelines for its development and selecting candidates for the Excellence in Librarianship Award ( Faculty Handbook, 1984, p. 26). The Council has considered policy measures regarding the schedule for fines, budget planning, growth of library, acquisition and circulation, and providing searching on bibliographic utilities. In 1988, the title of the Council was changed from Library Council to Council on Libraries, Computing and Information Systems, and its responsibilities were expanded to "review plans for and recommend policies for the development and operation of informational systems and technology as well as for library facilities" ( Faculty Handbook, 1989-90, p. 25).
  - University Life Council (ULC), 2005-2011; 15.9
  - University Planning and Policy Council (UPPC), 2004-2011; 15.10
  - Council on Academic Assessment (CAA), 2004-2011; 15.11
  - Committee on Ethics in Research and Scholarship (CERS), 2010-2011; 15.12
  - Council on Educational Policy, 1963-1998; 15.13; 4.5 cubic ft.
    This series contains agendas, minutes, correspondence, budget proposals, reports to the Senate, reports from sub-committees and other councils and memoranda relating to the council's responsibility for the oversight of campus planning and for the establishment of educational priorities. The council participates in the formulation and execution of the campus budget and evaluates the educational performance of the University as a whole and of its various components ( Faculty Handbook, 1984, pp. 18-19). Issues under consideration by the council include the budget, academic regulations, the curriculum, faculty work load, teaching excellence, enrollment and class size. The Council was originally created by the Graduate Council as a standing committee in 1961/62. The Council has three standing Committees, the Long-Range Planning Committee, the Resource Advisory Committee (formerly the Resource Allocation Committee), and the Evaluation Policy Committee (formerly the Program Evaluation Committee).
  - Student Affairs Council, 1966-1995; 15.14; 0.33 cubic ft.
    This series includes agendas, minutes, annual reports, reports to the Senate, bills and resolutions, and correspondence. This series also includes the records of the Interfaith Committee and the International Students Committee. The Council's concerns are to develop policies necessary to establish and maintain extracurricular programs and to make recommendations concerning University policy affecting student activities in these programs ( Faculty Handbook, 1984, p. 23). The Student Affairs council has dealt with the issues of campus relations, university communications (1971), alumni affairs, alcohol policy, student conduct, inspection of student housing (1973), policy regarding student records, campus ambulance service (1972-1973), and the SUNYA judicial system (1972-80). The Student Affairs Council was the successor to the Student Personnel Council, a college council independent of the Faculty Council ( Faculty Handbook, 1962, p. 20).
  - University Community Council, 1967-1998; 15.15; 0.75 cubic ft.
    This series includes agendas, minutes, annual reports, bills and legislation, correspondence, and reports to the Senate of the University Community Council. The council oversees university-wide matters, non-academic in nature, including external communications, operation of the University Auxiliary Service, and such policies affecting public safety, transportation, parking, etc. ( Faculty Handbook, 1984, p. 24). The predecessor to the University Community Council was the Committee on Community Liaison of the Faculty Council ( Faculty Handbook, 1962, p. 16).
    Also includes the records of the committees and policies established by the University Community Council. The University Community Council establishes policies regarding traffic and parking control, campus firearms policy (1973), the carrying of guns by security personnel, aesthetics of the campus environment, the skating rink proposal (1973), emeritus faculty privileges (1973), the 1970's gasoline shortage and its effects on the University, recycling programs, pets on campus, and the smoking policy(1996).